<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wp8 | C++/Python Jehad Fan Club]]></title>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/categories/wp8/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-02T22:58:32+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anton Akentiev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On WindowsPhone8]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/18/on-windowsphone8/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T22:47:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/18/on-windowsphone8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some say that WP8 &ldquo;rocks&rdquo;, MS will &ldquo;strike back&rdquo;, Nokia is a great company and so on&hellip; Unfortunately, while Microsoft tries hard to find new CEO &ndash;> it seems like nobody wants to write for WP8 platform.</p>

<h2>But(t) Why?</h2>

<p>Not because WP8 is good (or bad).
Not because WP8 has clear (or messy) interface.
Not because WP8 is Microsoft.</p>

<p>There is only one reason why i&rsquo;m not going to make some Windows Phone 8 applications in the near future: WP8 market share is too small. <strong>Imagine writing Desktop Application for Linux )) You will get nearly the same market share</strong></p>

<p>When starting to build app today i&rsquo;d rather consider this order:</p>

<pre><code> * Android. Yes! the paradigm is shifted, market tells us - first implement app for Android!
 * iOS
 * ... ooohhh, i need some rest
 * ... maybe we will do some WP8 research?
 * ... hey, MS gives all tools for free!
 * ... ok,ok. Some folks won their free Nokias and need WP8 app. I understand
 * WP8
</code></pre>

<p>Today i&rsquo;m going to start a list of Applications that are not available on WindowsPhone8 platform, but i NEED them. That is a real case scenario of mine, no fooling. Yes, the most basic apps are already in Windows Market, and some are not official. I will update this post, so new items will appear and some may become outdated.</p>

<h2>Let&rsquo;s start</h2>

<ol>
<li>airbnb.com</li>
<li>snapchat.com</li>
<li>gamecenter.nhl.com &ndash; &lsquo;National Hockey League&rsquo; streaming video app.</li>
<li>ozon.ru &ndash; One of the biggest russian online retailers.</li>
<li>sports.ru &ndash; One of the biggest russian online sports magazines. You can see Android + iPhone icons on their site. No WP8.</li>
<li>ska.ru &ndash; Russian hockey club.</li>
<li>feedly.com &ndash; Famous RSS reader (no official client, only 3rd party).</li>
<li>music.yandex.ru &ndash; Russian Pandora/Last.Fm clone ))</li>
<li>mobile.github.com &ndash; Oh, shhhhittt&hellip;</li>
<li>khlmobile.com &ndash; Again, Russian &lsquo;National Hockey League&rsquo; clone.</li>
<li>motocitizen.ru &ndash; Social network with no WP8 support! Ahahahah.</li>
<li>lenta.ru &ndash; No official client</li>
<li>URGENT! Dakar 2014 has only Android/iPhone clients!</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
