<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: venture | C++/Python Jehad Fan Club]]></title>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/categories/venture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-02T22:58:32+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anton Akentiev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeding the monster]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/feeding-the-monster/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T17:14:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/feeding-the-monster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Book &ldquo;Trust Me, I&rsquo;m Lying: Confessions of a Media Manipulator&rdquo; is written by Ryan Holiday, a young man in his late twenties who was a Director of Marketing of Ammerican Apparel. He has increased the sales from 40 to 60 millions dollars. Here is the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Trust-Me-Lying-Confessions-Manipulator-ebook/dp/B0074VTHH0">link</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.bnet.com/blogs/apparel-socks.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know who Lauren Phoenix is &ndash;> go see some porn (and she is one of the cutest girls in this business, trust me, i&rsquo;m not lying)). Simply type in &lsquo;Lauren Phoenix&rsquo; in your Google image search &ndash; i bet you will see American Apparel first)) They also featured Sasha Grey in their ads to make a real controversy and more pageviews.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d give this book 3 out of 5 stars. It is bit boring and i wonder if all that hype around this book is simply PR-manipulation (what this book&rsquo;s all about). Even though this book does not entertain much &ndash; it has many interesting examples of what &lsquo;marketing&rsquo; does today to our lives. In first part of the book author explains why media is working like that and what is their goal today.</p>

<p>Later author tells us why sources of pageviews are shifted from reliable (almost) agencies/newspapers to Twitter and Facebook. And why manipulations could be so easily done &ndash; nobody has time to verify the source.</p>

<p>He also states that RSS is already dead (book was published in 2012). That was a good foresight.</p>

<p>Ryan says that one day he understood that &ldquo;when manipulation is done &ndash; one wins, everybody looses&rdquo;. And he calls this manipulative behaviour &ldquo;Feeding the monster&rdquo;. He used to &ldquo;leak documents&rdquo;, orchestrated fake tweets and comments, painted some vulgar pharases over bilboards&hellip; If you want to understand how blogging/marketing/news work nowadays &ndash; read this book.</p>

<h1>Ready for quotes?</h1>

<p>&ldquo;Each one hopes that if he feeds the crocodile enough, the crocodile will eat him last&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Roughly half reported using Twitter to find and search stories&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Remember: every person in this ecosystem is under immense pressure to produce content under the tightest deadlines&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;…was once asked what he looked for when he hired writers for his blog. His answer was one word: quickness&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Millions of dollard are exhanged for essentially worthless assets&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Most important, they&rsquo;re at the mercy of Wikipedia, because that is where they do their research&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;If it doesn&rsquo;t spread &ndash; it&rsquo;s dead&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No marketer is ever going to push something with the stink of reasonableness, complexity or mixed emotions&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I have my own analysis: when you take away the question mark [from the title] it usually turns their headline into a lie&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It meant the decline of the editorial. These papers relied on gossip&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The Washington Post accidentally published a headline to an article about weather: SEO Headline&rdquo; ))</p>

<p>&ldquo;Publishers wish people liked better stuff&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;80% of blog posts contain fewer that 500 words&rdquo; &ndash; 800 words is the key number for blog post length</p>

<p>&ldquo;When you hear a friend say in conversation &lsquo;I was reading something…&rsquo; know that today the sad fact is that they probably just glanced at something on a blog&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;<em>May</em> becomes <em>Is</em> becomes <em>Has</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The common wisdom is that the site has [only] one second to make the hook&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The world is boring, but the news is exciting&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Thriller]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/the-thriller/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-23T23:41:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/the-thriller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Book &ldquo;Hatching Twitter: A True Story of Money, Power, Friendship, and Betrayal&rdquo; is written by Nick Bilton. Here is the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Hatching-Twitter-Story-Friendship-Betrayal/dp/1591846013">link</a>. It was released about two month ago.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.nickbilton.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/HatchingTwitter.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This is very engaging and entertaining book. I would rather call it &ldquo;Soap Twitter&rdquo; or &ldquo;Behind-the-scenes of Twitter&rdquo;. It is fast-paced and easy to read. This book is not about technology, but about people.</p>

<p>I was really surprised that Twitter was such a complete mess.</p>

<h3>Here are the quotes</h3>

<p><em>Person One:</em></p>

<p>&ldquo;I never considered you a founder&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What the fuck are you talking about? This is how VCs fuck up companies&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The board wants you to step up to the chairman role&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;As far as he knew, he was &lsquo;doing a great fucking job!&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I really have no fucking idea who to believe anymore&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What the fuck! So you&rsquo;re going behind his back to be CEO of the company! I can&rsquo;t believe it &hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p><em>Person Two:</em></p>

<p>&ldquo;He no longer looked like a himself: he began acting like the second coming of Steve Jobs&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What is the worst thing i can do as CEO to fuck the company up?&rdquo; &ndash;&ldquo;Hire your fucking friends!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He had watched in disbelief as he realized he&rsquo;d been completely erased from the Twitter history&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You&rsquo;re giving me more than i deserve?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;ll fire him, i&rsquo;ll quit&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You leave the office to early. You go off to you dressmaking classes&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He was acting like a cowboy&rdquo;</p>

<p><em>Person Three:</em></p>

<p>&ldquo;He is trying to push me out of company. I can feel it&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Just a few blocks away, he wandered alone in the rain as his former friends and cofounders toasted to the award they had just won without him&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A crimson stream of blood flowed down his cheek, past the drunken grin on his face&rdquo;</p>

<p><em>About Twitter:</em></p>

<p>&ldquo;If database goes down right now, we would lose everything&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;This is fucking war! This is out enemy. We need a war map. They&rsquo;re going to attack us&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We should go off and start our own Twitter&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not working for your fucking dot-coms&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I really appreciate our friendship and don&rsquo;t want me investing, or us working together, to affect it&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Blogger wasn&rsquo;t a traditional startup. It didn&rsquo;t have a pool table, a fridge full of beer&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;More vodka, more Red Bull, the digital music sounding like a tempo for each drink&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well! Well! How about you fucking be uncomfortable in reference to the entire fucking career of this guy? How about you be fucking uncomfortable?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He had cried hundreds of times over the years, cried a million tears. He had cried alone. In his bed&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Conslusion</h3>

<p>The book is 5/5. I highly recommend this reading. It is rated 4,5/5 on Amazon. So you can believe me. It is well written and i really enjoyed it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Launch Pad: Inside Y Combinator - book review]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2013/12/15/the-launch-pad-book-review/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-15T23:47:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2013/12/15/the-launch-pad-book-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Book &ldquo;The Launch Pad: Inside Y Combinator, Silicon Valley&rsquo;s Most Exclusive School for Startups&rdquo; is written by Randall Stross. Here is the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Launch-Pad-Combinator-Exclusive-Startups-ebook/dp/B00AFLLS3W">link</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/51a4sOz2THL._SY344_PJlook-inside-v2,TopRight,1,0_SH20_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h3>How to tell STARTUP from BUSINESS (even big)?</h3>

<p>Stross has good clear view of what &ldquo;startup&rdquo; means today: yes, it is only about fast pace and scalability. Everything that is not fast and scalable is ORDINARY BUSINESS. Kawasaki-Ries-Blank have said that many times.</p>

<p><em>Do you think Microsoft was a STARTUP in 80th?</em></p>

<p>The other interesting thought for me is probably about &ldquo;young means free&rdquo;. Author explains it in that way: we like youngsters not because they are smart and quick, but because they have no families and mortgages ))</p>

<h3>Quotes</h3>

<p><strong>On high stress in startups</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;Stress levels on our families were uncomfortably high &ndash; not something we&rsquo;d like to repeat&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;She says she was glad that she had not enjoyed a higher standard of living before coming to YC &ndash; it would have been harder to give up. We are giving up cafeteria food for ramen&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Is this how you want to spend the next 10 years?&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>On women in startups</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;Only 1.7 percent of venture capital-backed startups were founded by women&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Y combinator founded only 14 female founders to date&hellip;&rdquo; (2010)</p>

<p>&ldquo;There had been only 1 instance in which there had been an all-female team, a pair of cofounders&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;So she asked women in Berkeley&rsquo;s computer science department what toys they had played with as children &ndash; and whether Barbies were among them &ndash; and the answers she received were consistent: no Barbies. Legos were favorite toy&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Misc</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;Some say Europeans are less energetic, but i don&rsquo;t believe it. I think the problem with Europe is not that they lack balls, but that they lack examples&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The way to get really big returns is to do things that seem crazy &ndash; like starting a new search engine in 1998 or turning down a billion-dollar acquisition offer&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s so much luck involved with startups [that] you increase your odds of success by swinging the bat multiple times&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The cadence of startup life is speeding up considerably&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Conslusion</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;d give it 3+ out of 5 starts. I wanted to like this book, but there is not much new to me in it. Still, 3+ stars means that book is worth reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
