<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books | C++/Python Jehad Fan Club]]></title>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-02T23:54:32+06:00</updated>
  <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anton Akentiev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Books]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2015/03/30/new-books/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-30T23:07:51+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2015/03/30/new-books</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code class="javascript">Read books are far less valuable than unread ones ("Black Swan" by Nassim Taleb)
</code></pre>

<p>Hey-hey-hey, i&rsquo;m back. I was missing for about 5 month, it&rsquo;s time to update my little blog. I read whole bunch of books during this period of time. So this post is (again) a book-review. Let&rsquo;s select 5 most interesting <em>non-tech</em> books that i&rsquo;ve finished. Here they are:</p>

<h2>The signal and the noise: Why So Many Predictions Fail&ndash;but Some Don&rsquo;t</h2>

<p><img src="/images/SignalAndTheNoise.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>Wow. 9 out of 10. Very entertaining book about statistics, common misconceptions, prediction, probability, economics, forecasting earthquakes, etc.
The best book in this review, i think. Go and get one.</p>

<h2>The hard thing about hard things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers</h2>

<p><img src="/images/HardThings.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>The author is widely known Ben Horowitz - co-founder of Andreessen Horowitz venture capital company. Mustread. Couple of quotes for you:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The hard thing isn&rsquo;t (about) setting a big, hairy, audacious goal. The hard thing is laying people off when you miss the big goal. The hard thing is when those &ldquo;great people&rdquo; develop a sense of entitlement and start demanding unreasonable things.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Most business relationships either become too tense to tolerate or not tense enough to be productive after a while. Either people challenge each other to the point where they don&rsquo;t like each other or they become complacent about each other&rsquo;s feedback and no longer benefit from the relationship.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>My single biggest personal improvement as CEO occured on the day when i stopped being too positive.</p></blockquote></p>

<h2>The Black Swan</h2>

<p><img src="/images/BlackSwan.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p><strong>Classics</strong>.</p>

<p>From Wikipedia: &ldquo;The black swan theory or theory of black swan events is a metaphor that describes an event that comes as a surprise, has a major effect, and is often inappropriately rationalized after the fact with the benefit of hindsight&rdquo;. The event that comes as a black swan can&rsquo;t be &ldquo;risk managed&rdquo;. Remember 9/11 or recent economic crisis. These event are out of our scale of &ldquo;risk management&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Good but somewhat &ldquo;questionable&rdquo; book. Very interesting and mind-blowing. I recommend &ldquo;Fooled by Randomness&rdquo; (first one by Nassim Taleb) too.</p>

<h2>EDGY conversations: How Ordinary People Can Achieve Outrageous Success</h2>

<p><img src="/images/Edgy.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p><blockquote><p>You have to be more. You have to desperately want more. You have to care more. It matters that you waste time. It matters that you blame others for your failures. It matters that you are lazy at times.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The book is very good motivational read. If you need some motivation - read this book.
Main idea: hard-work is everything. You can do more than you think. There is nothing more to remember. 5 out of 10.</p>

<h2>Good to great: Why Some Companies Make The Leap And Others Don&rsquo;t</h2>

<p><img src="/images/GoodToGreat.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>Good is OK, but GREAT is way better. If you want to lead - you have to be great. The book is aimed primarily for the owners of a big company. However - many things are applicable for small startups. Main ideas that i remember )) goes here:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Level 5 leaders</strong> - no comment. Read the book.</li>
<li><strong>Hedgehog concept</strong> - do one thing, but do it GREAT.</li>
<li><strong>Crawl, walk, run</strong> - don&rsquo;t run when you see some opportunities. Keep thinking, then walk, only then run.</li>
<li><strong>There is no &ldquo;miracle moment&rdquo;</strong> - there is no one single &ldquo;miracle point&rdquo; how Google did it. It is all about continuous development.</li>
<li><strong>First-people, then-what</strong> - you need to understand your strengths and weaknesses before you can plan to succeed.</li>
</ol>


<p>One final qoute (not the most interesting one, but&hellip;) for you:
<blockquote><p>No company can grow revenues consistently faster than its ability to get enough of the right people to implement that growth and still become a great company.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The book is OK, but too &ldquo;dense&rdquo; and long. I wish it could be more entertaining and easy to read.</p>

<p>Thanks for coming!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add more value]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/06/26/add-more-value/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T21:47:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/06/26/add-more-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://anthonyakentiev.github.io/images/ninw.jpg">http://anthonyakentiev.github.io/images/ninw.jpg</a>&#8221; width=&#8221;300&#8221;></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Networking-Not-Working-Collecting-Connections-ebook/dp/B00K436RH8">book</a> is about adding more value to people&rsquo;s lives.
Author claims - you can really use your network of people to GET what you want from them. But you need to GIVE some EXTRA value.</p>

<p>Imagine - if your dentist helped you to find exceptional car dealer in town. He didn&rsquo;t have to. But he did.
So he added little value that will (in LONG term only) possibly give him good relations with you. Maybe you will get him new customer, maybe you will mention him somewhere.</p>

<p>Ideas shortly:</p>

<ul>
<li>Add value. Be &ldquo;ultimate connector&rdquo; or &ldquo;ultimate tiebreaker&rdquo; (both terms invented by author). Call your clients, help them do their job. Help them to find better attorney, car dealer, hockey rink, etc.</li>
<li>Be careful to connect people only with people you know well ))</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t attend &ldquo;networking events&rdquo; because &ldquo;networking is not working&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t wait for quick return. Be focused on long-term relationship with good people.</li>
<li>Business cards don&rsquo;t work.</li>
</ul>


<p>As to me - book is quite interesting, even though i have different opinion. I don&rsquo;t believe that these ideas helped author to really succeed in his business. The main problem is that these ideas will leave you unfocussed.
I think that it&rsquo;s better to be focused on giving people great value by doing your JOB, not by some extra means&hellip;</p>

<p>Imagine Steve Jobs spending his time calling you to ask if your bakery is OK. And suggesting you better one. That is simply waste of his time. He probably gave you more value by doing his direct job ) Maybe this is rude example, but &hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google and China]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/google-and-china/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T23:53:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/google-and-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The news is good today: i&rsquo;ve finished &ldquo;In The Plex: How Google Thinks, Works, and Shapes Our Lives&rdquo; book.</p>

<p><img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/9/95/In_the_Plex_Levy_2011.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h1>Brief</h1>

<p>I really liked this book, even though it is not as interesting as <a href="http://anthonyakentiev.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/the-thriller">this one</a>, but it gives you a quick glimpse of what big-business in America is.</p>

<p>What really inspired me - is that this book shows you - how you can redefine your future. You <strong>can</strong> build product(s) that will change people&rsquo;s lives.
When you read books aboud Apple and Steve Jobs - you think that their success is some kind of &lsquo;magic&rsquo;, but the book about Google clearly declares that technology must be in the first place. No marketing or PR bull-shit. Ever.</p>

<p>Here is the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Plex-Google-Thinks-Works-Shapes-ebook/dp/B003UYUP6M">link</a> to Amazon Store. The book is really big. It took me about 2 or 3 weeks to complete. There are many interesting things about Google in different periods. What i&rsquo;m going to &ldquo;review&rdquo; is a single chapter - Google invasion to China.</p>

<p>There were many struggles with China, and it seems that many projects (even Android and Google Wave) were easier to implement than to open chineese office )). More on that in &lsquo;quotes section&rsquo;.</p>

<h1>Quotes about China</h1>

<p>1) Most Chinese don&rsquo;t speak English. They will never use Google.</p>

<p>2) Google needs to be more close to Chinese people.</p>

<p>3) One woman seemed surprised that she&rsquo;s even be asked what search engine she uses. &ldquo;Baidu.&rdquo; Why? &ldquo;Because it is the product of Chinese people who naturally know more about China than Google&rdquo;, she said.</p>

<p>4) But by then, many Chinese had written off Google as an unwelcome outsider with less reliable service.</p>

<p>5) Baidu had succeeded in transforming the competition into a test of patriotism.</p>

<p>6) Other offices think they are Google. The Beijing office thinks it&rsquo;s Google China.</p>

<p>7) We&rsquo;d get these edicts from the Ministry of Information every day, and i had to sit there.</p>

<p>8) Your title is Product Manager&hellip; They objected that in China no one knew what that meant, and they preferred the official appellation of &ldquo;special assistant to Kai-Fu Lee&rdquo; ))</p>

<p>9) Kai-Fu Lee celebrity status had a downside. He became as much a part of the rumor mill as the celebrity female pop singers who dominated bulletin board discussions. Every time Google had a setback, word would appear that his departure was imminent ))</p>

<p>10) An exact transliteration of Google was out of question: it sounded too much like Gou-Gou, which meant &ldquo;dog-dog&rdquo; ))</p>

<p>11) Google angered the local press by not paying them &ldquo;red pockets&rdquo; (expense money that exceeded cab fare)</p>

<p>12) Often manager of Internet-cafes would take money to replace one search engine with another. Google generally avoided such arrangements. But the company sometimes used representatives who weren&rsquo;t as finicky and looked the other way.</p>

<p>13) It was as if the government was sending Google a message: you can be in our market, but you must not be the leader.</p>

<p>14) Wang explained that such acts are not uncommon in China, where there&rsquo;s a &ldquo;more fluid&rdquo; view of plagiarism.</p>

<p>15) It&rsquo;s not that i don&rsquo;t trust Chinese engineers, it&rsquo;s the same engineers as here, who went to the same schools, but when you go to a place like China, there&rsquo;s lots of examples of companies where intellectual property has gone out that door.</p>

<p>16) The officials were not impressed. &ldquo;This is the antiporn year,&rdquo; they said. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve been warned twice before, and this is the third time. So we are going to punish you.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Stay tuned!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[To ZigZag or not to ZigZag]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/to-zigzag-or-not-to-zigzag/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T22:56:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/to-zigzag-or-not-to-zigzag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not really into this book, but it has one though that i liked: &ldquo;First step in any business is getting profitability&rdquo;. Of course, there are a lot of business that are exceptions to this statement. You can easily recall YouTube and Twitter for example.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.zigzagprinciple.com/wp-content/themes/xmuz/images/book-home.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>So that was Zig#1.</p>

<p>Zig#2 is &ldquo;Once you are profitable - add additional resources&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Zig#3 is &ldquo;Scale your business&rdquo;. Don&rsquo;t keep baking bread, spread the technology, so you will control many bakeries.</p>

<p>Author starts  with little story of &ldquo;zigzagging through obstacles instead of going downhill straight to your goal&rdquo;. But  i still wonder why these <strong>straightforward</strong> steps are called <strong>ZigZags</strong> ))</p>

<p>Here is the <a href="http://www.zigzagprinciple.com">link</a>. Every book has own domain/site today?</p>

<h1>Quotes:</h1>

<p>&ldquo;What skills do i have that can get me to profitability the fastest?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;First step in building foundation is assesing your resources&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;During this first Zig, it is important to remember that you are not going to have time to be perfect at everything. Many people that are perfectionsts or have a methodological personality fail at this stage because they try to be great and
have everything perfect and buttoned up…&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We worked fast and we worked hard, which meant we didn&rsquo;t always refine our effort to the point of perfection. In fact, in many cases we settled for <strong>good enough</strong>&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A key reason many people have hard time adding a resource is they have become accustomed to micromanaging every aspect of their business&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Mental Capital (our knowledge, skills, talents, passions) + Raltionship Capital (quality of our relationships with a broad pool of people) = Financial Capital&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Most people spend 80% of their time worrying about things they can not control. In other words, they spend all of their time and energy focusing on their areas of concern rather than their area of influence&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Entrepreneurship is having the courage to wander in the fog&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A goal needs to be: (1)written down, (2)measurable, (3)realistic&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Resist change and die, adapt to change and survive, create change and thrive&rdquo;</p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>Don&rsquo;t buy <em>&ldquo;Become Next Steve Jobs in 30 minutes&rdquo;</em>-style books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeding the monster]]></title>
    <link href="http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/feeding-the-monster/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T17:14:00+06:00</updated>
    <id>http://AnthonyAkentiev.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/feeding-the-monster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Book &ldquo;Trust Me, I&rsquo;m Lying: Confessions of a Media Manipulator&rdquo; is written by Ryan Holiday, a young man in his late twenties who was a Director of Marketing of Ammerican Apparel. He has increased the sales from 40 to 60 millions dollars. Here is the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Trust-Me-Lying-Confessions-Manipulator-ebook/dp/B0074VTHH0">link</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.bnet.com/blogs/apparel-socks.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know who Lauren Phoenix is -> go see some porn (and she is one of the cutest girls in this business, trust me, i&rsquo;m not lying)). Simply type in &lsquo;Lauren Phoenix&rsquo; in your Google image search - i bet you will see American Apparel first)) They also featured Sasha Grey in their ads to make a real controversy and more pageviews.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d give this book 3 out of 5 stars. It is bit boring and i wonder if all that hype around this book is simply PR-manipulation (what this book&rsquo;s all about). Even though this book does not entertain much - it has many interesting examples of what &lsquo;marketing&rsquo; does today to our lives. In first part of the book author explains why media is working like that and what is their goal today.</p>

<p>Later author tells us why sources of pageviews are shifted from reliable (almost) agencies/newspapers to Twitter and Facebook. And why manipulations could be so easily done - nobody has time to verify the source.</p>

<p>He also states that RSS is already dead (book was published in 2012). That was a good foresight.</p>

<p>Ryan says that one day he understood that &ldquo;when manipulation is done - one wins, everybody looses&rdquo;. And he calls this manipulative behaviour &ldquo;Feeding the monster&rdquo;. He used to &ldquo;leak documents&rdquo;, orchestrated fake tweets and comments, painted some vulgar pharases over bilboards&hellip; If you want to understand how blogging/marketing/news work nowadays - read this book.</p>

<h1>Ready for quotes?</h1>

<p>&ldquo;Each one hopes that if he feeds the crocodile enough, the crocodile will eat him last&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Roughly half reported using Twitter to find and search stories&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Remember: every person in this ecosystem is under immense pressure to produce content under the tightest deadlines&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;…was once asked what he looked for when he hired writers for his blog. His answer was one word: quickness&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Millions of dollard are exhanged for essentially worthless assets&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Most important, they&rsquo;re at the mercy of Wikipedia, because that is where they do their research&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;If it doesn&rsquo;t spread - it&rsquo;s dead&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No marketer is ever going to push something with the stink of reasonableness, complexity or mixed emotions&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I have my own analysis: when you take away the question mark [from the title] it usually turns their headline into a lie&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It meant the decline of the editorial. These papers relied on gossip&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The Washington Post accidentally published a headline to an article about weather: SEO Headline&rdquo; ))</p>

<p>&ldquo;Publishers wish people liked better stuff&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;80% of blog posts contain fewer that 500 words&rdquo; - 800 words is the key number for blog post length</p>

<p>&ldquo;When you hear a friend say in conversation &lsquo;I was reading something…&rsquo; know that today the sad fact is that they probably just glanced at something on a blog&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;<em>May</em> becomes <em>Is</em> becomes <em>Has</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The common wisdom is that the site has [only] one second to make the hook&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;The world is boring, but the news is exciting&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
